JATIN KALRA

H No. 926 Saraswati Vihar, MG Road, Gurgaon, Haryana 122002 (M) +2348056491144

E-mail: jatinkalra2006@gmail.com

Profile & Career Objective:

To work in challenging atmosphere and put my potential to the best in fulfilling Organization's goal and learning maximum through consistent hard work and determination.

Summary of Experience:

Security Specialist with over **10 years** of experience in Network Security & Information Security.

Expert in planning, Implementation and maintenance of Information Security solutions in direct support of business objectives.

Specializes in security administration and engineering, Internal audits, Compliance audits, New technology evaluation, Incident Analysis, Change and Problem management & Vulnerability Assessment.

Have ability to work efficiently as a Leader, Team Member & Individual.

Skills Summary:

- Proficient in Local (LAN) and Wide Area Networking (WAN).
- Knowledge and experience of Server configuration of Apache, Squid, Send Mail, FTP and DNS etc.
- Hardware Installation, configuration and troubleshooting for all Computer, Network devices and Firewalls.
- Configuration of IPSO, Fortinet and Checkpoint.
- Configuration and Installation of Blue Coat Proxy.
- Trained on ISO-27001:2005 Security Certification.
- Understanding and implementation of customers Security polices and facilitates audits.
- Instrumental in internal security audits for various clients.
- Performing POCs for various products.
- Ability to learn and adapt new technology in a fast growing IT environment.
- Possess Excellent Analytical, Research and implementation skills.

Professional Experience:

Seven-Up Bottling Company PLC Lagos, Nigeria

Sept 2014 - Till Date

Network Operations Manager: Roles and Responsibilities

- Manage day to day operations and enhancements, plan for new initiatives for growth of the organization.
- Responsible for managing team of dedicated InfoSec and BCP for over 4 countries.

- Lead infrastructure, technical system and application implementation discussions with technical engineers, contractors and vendors.
- Project Leader of VAPT, Network devices audit, network architecture review and desktop compliance review.
- Carrying out information security risk assessments and functioning as an internal auditor for security issues
- Work on and complete multiple projects and deliverables with limited supervision, and work independently or in a small team environment.
- Managing Information Security Procurement Evaluation, Recommendation and Procurement
- Closely monitoring incident management process and conducting security breach investigations
- Responsible for managing Windows/Linux server (database, email, application, data), network clients, remote location, broadband connections and VPN.

Wipro InfoTech Ltd. Gurgaon, India

Nov 2011 - Sept 2014

Program Lead: Roles and Responsibilities

- Deployed at Client Site for Managing Infrastructure Security Operation and End User Computing.
- On Board for CAB, responsible for evaluating changes, associated risks & rollback plans and approve accordingly.
- Conduct POC for Infrastructure Security Solutions.
- Conduct threat and vulnerability assessment of test lab and provide technical expertise, recommendations on mitigating the security risks.
- Co-ordination with Front Office team.
- Technical operations and is defined as contributor/owner to End point security from Subject Matter Expert standpoint.
- Duties involves participation in managing technologies, evaluating new technologies, continuous improvement of SLA, customer meetings, implementing new solutions as asked by customer.
- Maintain active participation in Security operations of other IT infrastructure components.
- Technologies include Symantec, McAfee, TrendMicro, Microsoft, Bluecoat, Device control and System security areas.
- Managing compliance with information security policies and standards, vulnerability remediation, Security Audits and responsible for audit preparation.
- Responsible for facilitating issues resolution, preparing & presenting timely status reports to client & internal senior management.
- Defining and directing project goals, objectives, critical success factors, milestones and risks.
- Improving quality results by evaluating and upgrading processes, directing changes in the infrastructure.

Orange Business Services Gurgaon, India

May 2008 - Sept 2011

Security Administrator: Roles and Responsibilities

- Reviewing, analyzing and troubleshooting network traffic.
- Reviewing and analyzing firewall alerts, logs and configurations.

- Responsible for handling both re-active (customer call) and pro-active (monitoring) incidents related to various security devices like Firewalls, Proxies, UTMs (Fortinet), IPS/IDS, SSL VPN and Anti Virus servers.
- As the owner of the technical resolution, provide Root Cause Analysis (RCA) and Reason for Outage (RFO) reports.
- Managing complex change requests according to Orange Business Services change control process.
- Assuring all changes are submitted, approved, implemented and reviewed in a suitable and agreed manner.
- Involved in problem management as the owner of the technical resolutions.
- Audit systems using vulnerability scanners and manual techniques to verify system security settings and configurations.
- Responsible for providing online high-end technical support to corporate customers.
- Planning and executing changes and upgrades to the Firewalls.
- Planning and Implementing of Disaster Recovery for Firewalls
- Maintaining the Nokia IP Security Platform, Netscreen Juniper, Checkpoint, Fortinet & Bluecoat Proxy.
- Participation in SAS-70, ISO 20K & ISO 27K successful certification.
- Assistance in designing Enterprise security standards, Policies and guidelines.
- Working as on-call (out of office hours) as and when required.

Hughes Communication India Ltd (HCIL) Gurgaon, India

May 2006 - May 2008

Network Engineer: Roles and Responsibilities

- Maintaining the Hub equipments & ensuring high uptime of NOC.
- Configuration of Internet Information Service (IIS), Firewall and Antivirus Software.
- Design/configuration and management of security devices for different business requirements for the company.
- Monitoring Real-time logs of Firewall.
- Checkpoint Firewall management (NG/NG-AI/NGX).
- Firewalls, Security Policy Design
- Design, configuration and management of bandwidth management devices-Packet Shapers (Packeteer 6500 series, 2500 series, 4500 series) and Bandwidth Managers.
- Configuration, monitoring and management of CISCO 1600, 2500, 2600 series routers.
- DNS and DHCP setup with Red hat enterprise Linux and user management which includes Configuration of mail servers, FTP servers and web servers.
- Coordination with vendor for making network infrastructure up as per customer requirement.
- Managing co-location web servers; maintaining backups; maintaining inhouse production mail, squid and DNS servers.
- Creating and presenting daily, weekly and monthly reports for Network and ISP related issues
- Providing RCA for Security Incidents to top management.

HCL Infosystems Ltd. Chandigarh, India

Dec 2005 -May 2006.

OJT: Role & Responsibilities

- Installation of all Hardware Devices.
- Coordinated site surveys and provided Demos to the Clients
- Installation and Maintenance of Windows & Linux based servers.
- Network planning and installation
- Onsite Installation & Troubleshooting.

Academic Qualifications:

- Executive MBA (Distance Education) in Marketing (2010-2011) from Vinayaka Missions University, Tamil Naidu.
- **Bachelor of Engineering (B.E)** in Electronics & Communication (2001-2005) from Dronacharya College of Engineering, Gurgaon.
- Passed AISSCE (Senior Secondary Examinations) in 2001 from CBSE.
- Passed **AISSE** (Higher Secondary Examinations) in 1999 from CBSE.

Certifications:

- Checkpoint Certified Security Administrator (CCSA) Certified.
- Nokia Certified Security Associate (NCSA) Certified.
- Nokia Certified Voice Associate (NCVA) Certified.
- ITIL 2011 Foundation Certified.
- Blue Coat Certified Proxy Administrator (BCCPA) Certified.

Personal Details:

Date of Birth: 7th April, 1983

Father's Name: Mr. Vijay Kumar Kalra Contact Number (Home): +91-124-4036324

Passport Number: L7548167
Marital Status: Married

Permanent Address: H No. 926, Saraswati Vihar, MG Road, Gurgaon,

Haryana-122002

Date:

Place: (JATIN KALRA)